# Nick Karlaftis

Address: Adamantiou Korai 31A, Thessaloniki, GR

Mobile Phone: (+30) 6937183714 Email: NikoKarlS3@gmail.com

#### C# / .NET / SQL Developer

Eager to put .NET/SQL-oriented skills to use, utilising the advantages of Microsoft's latest technologies, to create reliable and high-standard applications.

### **Professional Profile**

Accomplished C# developer with 5+ years' experience on full system development lifecycle, including designing and implementing various applications. My primary goal is to apply my technical expertise by bringing key principles of software engineering, while staying up to date on the latest programming trends and technologies. My international experience and communication skills can be a multi applicable asset.

## **Areas of Expertise**

.NET Technologies & Frameworks	Software Application Tools
<ul> <li>.NET Framework /.Net Core</li> <li>C# (LINQ, knowledge of functional paradigm)</li> <li>Dapper / EF Core</li> <li>Rest API (MediatR / Minimal APIs)</li> <li>Fluent Validation &amp; Assertions</li> <li>Refit / Polly</li> <li>xUnit / NUnit</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Visual Studio, VS Code, Rider</li> <li>Git, Tortoise SVN</li> <li>MS SQL, PostgreSQL</li> <li>Azure Cloud (basic)</li> <li>Azure DevOps (basic)</li> <li>Docker</li> <li>Postman / Redis</li> </ul>
Software Architecture	Design Patterns-Principles
<ul><li>Clean Architecture</li><li>DDD</li></ul>	<ul><li>SOLID Principles</li><li>Various creational, structural and behavioural patterns</li></ul>

## **Professional Experience**

C# Developer • EmDot S.A. • Athens, GR December 2019 to present

Developed, maintained and drove the evolvement of IoT related APIs, in the fields of waste management and roadside assistance.

Delivered solid software solutions for the shipbroking industry.

- Designed and implemented C# windows applications.
- Developed integration services/daemons using various APIs, ranging from mere vessel tracking up to more elaborate systems like XLedger ERP.
- Refactored and maintained legacy system and got involved in migrating parts of it to a next generation system in .Net.
- Set up monitoring infrastructure system using Bosun and Docker hosted on an Azure Linux server.

Delphi Developer • Altec S.A. • Thessaloniki, GR

November 2010 to April 2011

My academic internship was fulfilled in Altec Software.

- Internship main task involved maintenance of an E.R.P.
- The tools used for the development were: Delphi 6, Microsoft SQL Server, PL/SQL.

## **Personal Projects**

### **CRM for Pharmacy Store**

December 2014 to January 2015

Designed and developed a commercial CRM desktop application for a pharmacy store. Comprehensively the application supports operations for Sales, Customers, Product and Charts. The application was implemented using the below tools: C# WinForms, MySQL

### **Education**

2006 – 2012

Department of Informatics and Computer Technology, Technological Education Institute of West Macedonia, Kastoria (Greece)

### **National Service**

2018 – 2019

Served in the Signals Arm as operator of digital terminal devices and cryptographic machines